A Guide to the Additional Papers of Alan Cheuse,
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Additional Papers of Alan Cheuse 1971-1998
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10726-p,-q
This collection consists of ca. 3,200 items (10 Hollinger boxes, ca. 4 linear shelf feet).
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Alan Cheuse of Fairfax, Virginia, placed his papers on loan to the Library on May 29, 1997 and August 22, 1998. The papers were purchased by the Library on September 11, 2003.
Scope and Content Information
This collection consists of the additional papers of the American author, book reviewer, and George Mason University professor, Alan Cheuse, ca. 3,200 items (10 Hollinger boxes, ca. 4 linear shelf feet), ca. 1971-1998. These papers include manuscripts for articles, speeches, interviews, and short stories; book reviews, both published and for All Things Considered on National Public Radio; screen plays; cassette tape recordings, computer disks, and a video cassette "Carlos Fuentes: Man of Two Worlds;" printed material; contracts and royalties; passports; photographs and drawings; correspondence; research material; short stories by other authors; appointment calendars; short stories used in The Sound of Writing; and a collection of short stories assembled for publication as Lost and Old Rivers. Other book manuscripts include The Light Possessed and On Earth as It Is.
Contents List
- SERIES I: CORRESPONDENCE and TOPICAL FILES
  - Appointment Calendars 1996-1997 (Box 1)
  - Biographical Material for Alan Cheuse n.d. (Box 1)
  - Contracts and Royalties 1987-1998 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence (6 folders) 1983-1988 May (Box 1)
  - Correspondence (7 folders) 1988 Jun-1996 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence (6 folders) 1997 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence (5 folders) 1998 Jan-Sep, n.d. (Box 4)
  - Correspondence - E-mail (2 folders) 1997-1998 Mar (Box 4)
  - Correspondence - Post cards 1987-1998, n.d. (Box 5)
  - Literary Events, Conferences, Workshops, etc. (4 folders) 1985-1998, n.d. (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous Material ca. 1995-1998, n.d. (Box 5)
  - Passports and Vaccination Record 1980-1986 (Box 6)
  - Photographs and Drawings 1984-1998 (Box 6)
  - Printed Materials, including catalogs, news clippings, and newsletters ca. 1984-1998 (Box 6)
  - Reviews of Books written by Alan Cheuse 1986-1998 (Box 6)
- SERIES II: MANUSCRIPTS BY ALAN CHEUSE
  - Articles by Alan Cheuse 1987-1998, n.d. (Box 6)
  - Article by Alan Cheuse - "Tacos and Manna" in San Diego Weekly Reader 1997 (Box 6)
  - Article by Alan Cheuse - "Tacos and Manna" in San Diego Weekly Reader- Research Material 1987-1997 (Box 6)
  - Fall Out of Heaven- Miscellaneous 1987, n.d. (Box 6)
  - Interview of Alan Cheuse by Sonya Cheuse for Oh, Freedom 1996 (Box 6)
  - The Light Possessed A Novel- New Front Matter and Pages for the reprint 1998 Mar (Box 6)
  - Lost and Old Rivers, TMs, with editor's comments 1997 Nov-Dec (Box 6)
  - Lost and Old Rivers, Page Proofs, Inside Layout 1998 Jun 17 (Box 7)
  - Lost and Old Rivers, Page Proofs, Inside Layout, and Dust Jacket Artwork 1998 Jun 29 (Box 7)
  - Lost and Old Rivers, Page Proofs, Corrected 1998 Jul (Box 7)
  - Lost and Old Rivers- Miscellaneous Correspondence and Notes 1997-1998 (Box 7)
  - On Earth As It Is, TMs, Incomplete n.d. (Box 7)
  - Reviews written by Alan Cheuse, last folder includes reviews of multiple titles (5 folders) 1984-1998, n.d. (Box 8)
  - Script for a Play [Rule of Thumb?] n.d. (Box 8)
  - Short Stories A-T (4 folders) 1988-1997, n.d. (Box 9)
  - Short Story - "On the Millstone River" n.d. (Box 9)
  - The Sound o f Writing Programs and Production Schedules 1995-1996 (Box 10)
  - The Sound o f Writing Short Stories (2 folders) ca. 1995 (Box 10)
  - Speech at Ground Breaking Ceremony for Russell Avenue Apartments 1997 Nov 18 (Box 10)
  - Squaw Valley Community of Writers Lecture "On the Contemporary" 1998 Aug 8 (Box 10)
  - Works by Other Writers, including Emma Cheuse (2 folders) 1971-1998, n.d. (Box 10)
  - Works by Other Writers - Children A Treatment by Richard Ford 1988 (Box 10)
- SERIES III: CASSETTE TAPE RECORDINGS, COMPUTER DISKS, and VIDEO
  - Audiocassette 0018 no. 1 "Writing Short Fiction" by Alan Cheuse, produced by Davenport Productions (2 copies) 1988 (Box 10)
  - Audiocassette 0018 no.2 "Holiday Books" All Things Considered, National Public Radio (2 copies) 1997 Dec 10 (Box 10)
  - Audiocassette 0018 no.3 All Things Considered, National Public Radio 1998 Jun 5 (Box 10)
  - Audiocassette 0018 no.4 Sound of Writing One Programs 1, 2, 3 n.d. (Box 10)
  - Audiocassette 0018 no.5 Sound of Writing One Programs 7, 8, 9 n.d. (Box 10)
  - Audiocassette 0018 no.6 "A Halloween Journey" n.d. (Box 10)
  - Audiocassette 0018 no.7 Interview of Alan Cheuse on "The Writer's Corner" at the University of Virginia n.y. Nov 2 (Box 10)
  - Computer Disk 0002 no.1-4 Biography of an Unknown Woman(4 disks) ca. 1996 (Box 10)
  - Computer Disk 0002 no.5 On the Millstone River n.d. (Box 10)
  - Computer Disk 0002 no.6 On Earth As It Is, 3rd Draft 1995 Summer (Box 10)
  - Computer Disk 0002 no.7 Rowing In Eden, Pre-pages through Chapter 74 n.d. (Box 10)
  - Videocassette 0048 "Carlos Fuentes: Man of Two Worlds" (57:45) by Albert Casciero and Joel Foreman 1988 (Box 10)